Guide to the Theodore L. Badger Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Theodore L. Badger papers
1913-1980
MS 1385
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
(2 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, writings, printed matter, photographs, and minutes and reports relating primarily to Theodore Badger's term on the board of directors of the International Grenfell Association.
Badger, Theodore L.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Theodore L. Badger, 1984-1986.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Theodore L. Badger Papers contain material documenting Dr. Badger's affiliation with the International Grenfell Association (I.G.A.). Theodore Badger, colleague and friend of Sir Wilfred Grenfell, served on the Board of Directors of the I.G.A. from 1948-1975 and was chairman from 1952-1953. The papers consist of correspondence, writings, printed matter, photographs, and I.G.A. minutes and reports. Dr. Badger's correspondence with Sir Wilfred and Lady Ann Grenfell is of particular interest.
The Theodore L. Badger Papers were donated to Yale University by Mrs. Badger in 1984.
Medical care -- Canada; Missions -- Newfoundland and Labrador; Canada; Labrador (N.L.); Newfoundland and Labrador; Photoprints; Physicians; Badger, Theodore L.; Grenfell, Wilfred Thomason, Sir, 1865-1940; International Grenfell Association
- Inventory
  - Correspondence
    - A-Z, 1926-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Curtis, Charles, 1937-1960, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Fowler, Emily A., 1926-1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Grenfell, Lady Ann, 1923-1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Grenfell, Pascoe, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Grenfell, Sir Wilfred, 1927-1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Grenfell, Wilfred Jr., 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Mack, Harold R., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Maier, William M., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Spalding, K., 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Whitman, Alfred A., 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Writings and Printed Matter
    - Articles from I.G.A. publication Among the Deep Sea Fishes, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Biographical sketch of Wilfred T. Grenfell, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Clippings, 1938-1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Notes on:
      - Montagnais Indians, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Labrador, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Memorial University meeting, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Printed matter, 1948-1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Profiles of individuals associated with the Grenfell Mission in Labrador and photographs (Box 1, Folder 19 - 21)
    - Report: "The Use of Transparent Cellulose Film for Insulation", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Typescript by Wilfred T. Grenfell, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Typescript: unidentified, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - International Grenfell Association
    - Minutes, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Minutes, 1927-1979 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Report to the Board of Directors, 1946 November (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Report to the Executive Committee, 1947 October (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Report on the Preliminary Survey of the International Grenfell Association, 1964 April (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Reports, addresses, 1972-1977 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Reports on the future of I.G.A., 1977 November 7, 1977 March 7 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Report of the Meeting at the Committee on Northern Health and Medicine in Newfoundland and Labrador, 1978 April 6 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Annual Report of the Executive Director, 1979 June (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Annual Report: Northwest River Hospital and Nursing Stations; correspondence, 1979-1980, 1980 May 5-July 14 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Supporting Associations: statements of incorporation, 1913-1961 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Supporting Associations: New England Grenfell Association, 1971-1980 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - By-laws, rules, regulations: St. Anthony Hospital, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Photographs
    - Envelope no. 1: Sir Wilfred Grenfell and Donald B. MacMillan (1), 1931 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Envelope no. 2: Sir Wilfred Grenfell, fish drying, Red Bay gardens (6), 1932 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Envelope no. 3: Ragged Islands (1), 1933 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Envelope no. 4: Sir Wilfred Grenfell and puppies (2), 1930 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Envelope no. 5: Jim Tucker, the cabbage patch (3), 1932 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Envelope no. 6: Sir Wilfred Grenfell, Dr. Curtis, St. Anthony's Hospital (1), 1930 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Envelope no. 7: Albert Ash (1), 1930 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Envelope no. 8: Pascoe Grenfell with cod fish (1), 1931 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Envelope no. 9: Will Stilas (1), 1931 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Envelope no. 10: Sir Wilfred, Capt. Kean and others on the bridge of the Prospero (1), 1931 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Envelope no. 11: Jack Watt (1), 1929 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Envelope no. 12: Joe Michelin (2), 1930 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Envelope no. 13: Sir Wilfred with boy on crutches (1), 1930 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Envelope no. 14: Will Simmas (2), 1933 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Envelope no. 15: Lady Grenfell (2), 1930? (Box 2, Folder 38)